<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on ng&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://nareshganesan.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on ng&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2016 15:46:50 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://nareshganesan.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>1000Lookz - Virtual Tryon</title>
      <link>https://nareshganesan.github.io/post/1000Lookz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2016 15:46:50 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nareshganesan.github.io/post/1000Lookz/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Its been couple of months since I started working for 1000Lookz/VDime.
The journey has been really wonderful so far. Everyday I get to work on cool technologies.
Python has been the bread and butter @ &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.1000lookz.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;1000Lookz&lt;/a&gt;.
We are company that specialises in CV, machine learning and Deep Learning.
Some of the day to day techology we use @ &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.1000lookz.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;1000Lookz&lt;/a&gt; have been listed below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;technologies:192998f09a0e3f2eb93de662239c080a&#34;&gt;Technologies&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DL&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Caffe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CV&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dlib&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OpenCV&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tesseract&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ocropy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are a virtual makeover company specialising on virtual tryon.
Some of our current solutions include Tryon make over, Tryon Eyewear, Tryon Jewelry and much more to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are also working on our properitory OCR products for documents, Bills, Forms and Certificates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fun part is the research we do everyday to solve some  cool machine learning problems.
I&amp;rsquo;m not good at blogging so please bear with me.
I will be adding more about 1000Lookz and the technology frequently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please feel free to ask any questions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tornado</title>
      <link>https://nareshganesan.github.io/post/Tornado/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2016 05:34:27 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nareshganesan.github.io/post/Tornado/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tornado is a asynchronous non blocking network I/O web framework / library. Tornado is really useful for applications which require a long-lived connection to each user.
It can easily serve upto Ten&amp;rsquo;s of thousands of open connection at a time. It can also comes bundled with a HTTP server which makes it perfect for a web server which could
easily serve tens of thousands of connections. This really a huge deal, if you have dealt with synchronous blocking servers. In a typical synchrous web servers, the
client has to wait for the request to complete and the server is blocked until the response is sent back to client.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the number of request to synchronous servers increase, the number of blocked requests waiting for a response increases. This makes the web servers
overloaded with requests and eventually making them crash. In traditional web application using synchronous web servers, companies make another
load balancing layer to route the request to different servers based on the servers traffic. The crucial point to note here is the architecture of the
web application is made to accomodate more traffic by adding more web servers coupled with load balancers. Here, the traditional synchronous servers have some serious
bottleneck with handling huge traffic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the advent of Web 3.0, data is exploding in higher order polynomial terms which I can&amp;rsquo;t imagine. The need to handle more web traffic would be a basic requirement.
Tornado is a next gen networking library to test and play.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First post using Hugo</title>
      <link>https://nareshganesan.github.io/post/First-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 18:52:10 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nareshganesan.github.io/post/First-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is my first blog post using &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;, the new static site generator.  I&amp;rsquo;ve always to wanted to start blog to share and learn.
Its never late than now. :) Hugo is really neat, simple and easy to install. Learning curve is easy to moderate,
depends on the person. I will write more about the Hugo in my future posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, I&amp;rsquo;m in the process of building the blog template, so will be making more changes to the template.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>